Dorothy Smith Dushkin Papers, 1906-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Series V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
  - Recordings
    - Reel-to-reel recordings of Dorothy Smith Dushkin compositions (some tapes include other composers)
      - "Quintet for Amanda" for oboe and string quartet: Roy Lawrence, oboe; Mary Jane Metcalf, violin I; Colin Murdoch, violin II; Kathy Jelson, viola; Marti Kanir, cello; Kinhaven Jul 1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - "Quintet for Flute and Strings" (1962), recorded 14 Jul 1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - "Quintet for Horn and Strings": Dennis Behm, french horn; Colin Murdoch, violin I; Marcia Edson, violin II; Kathy Jelson, viola; Marti Kanir, cello Kinhaven July 1974 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - "Septet for Brass" (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - "Pour S'Amuser": Randall Edson, marimba; Daniel Maki, flute; Mark Perchanok, oboe; Joseph Contino, clarinet; Robert Moore, bassoon (Box 11)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Orchestra": Kay Moore, pianist; Kinhaven Orchestra Summer 1974 (Box 11)
      - "Sonata for Bassoon and Piano": Kay Moore, piano; Bob Moore, bassoon (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - "Sonata for Horn": Dennis Behm, horn; Charles Hamlen, piano; ("first movement played too fast both times") (Box 11)
      - "Sonata for Flute and Piano": Peter Schultz, flute; Randall Edson and Kay Moore, piano (original tape, uncut) 15 Aug 1978 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - "Sonata for Flute and Piano" (edited copy) (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - "Sonata for Two Violincelli": Nancy Bidlack, cello; James Kennedy, cello; Jerry Bidlack, piano (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - "Songs of the Bards of Bengal": Chamber Singers, Daisietta Kim, conductor; Kinhaven Aug 1972 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - "Tapestry: Suite for String Orchestra and Percussion": The Kinhaven Orchestra, Jerry Bidlack, conductor; 23 Jul 1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - "Ten Poems in a Filagree": Lehigh Women's Choir, Jerry Bidlack, conductor, with flute, string quartet, and piano; Bicentennial Concert 28 Mar 1976 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - "Ten Poems in a Filagree": (same as #26) (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - "Theme and Variations for Piano and Chamber Orchestra," summer 1982 (Box 11, Folder 27a)
      - "Trio" for piano, violin, and cello (also includes pieces by other composers), fourth staff concert 24 Jul 1976 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Twelfth student concert (pieces by other composers) 14 Aug 1976 (Box 11)
      - "Trio Sonata for Viola, Cello, and Piano": M. J. [Metcalf?], Nancy [Bidlack?], Charles [?] (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Pieces by other composers
      - "Triptych": Kinhaven Orchestra, Jerry Bidlack, conductor Jul 1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - "Quintet for Flute and Strings": Peter, Diana, Marcia, M. J., Nancy; 14 Jul 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Claviquint No. 1," student performance 29 Jul 1979 (Box 11)
      - Special Concert ("Fantasy for Three"; "Sonata for Two Celli and Piano," movement 1; "Retrospective"; "Diversion for Four Hands and Percussion), 14 Aug 1979 (Box 11)
      - "Triptych" (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Allen Shawn, "Cabaret Music" and "Movements for Violin and Piano", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Scores
    [For more detailed information about scores, see the supplemental list prepared by Thomas G. MacCracken]
    - Orchestral works
      - Concerto for Piano and Orchestra," (manuscript); "Piano Concerto: Reduced Score Sketch, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Orchestra": full score (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Orchestra": parts (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - "Kinhaven Concerto" (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "Salutation Fanfare" (Box 12, Folder 4a)
      - "Tapestry: Suite for String Orchestra" (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - "Theme and Variations for Piano and Chamber Orchestra" (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "Three Patterns in C, or Holiday Suite" for the younger orchestra (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Triptych" (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Chamber music
      - "Antiphonal Chorale" for brass choirs (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - "April Quintet" for woodwinds and piano (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - "Brass and Piano Quartet" for trumpet, horn, trombone, and piano (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - "Claviquint No. I" for woodwinds and piano (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - "Claviquint No. II" for woodwinds and piano (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - "Claviquint No. III" for flute, horn, strings, and piano 1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - "Diversion" for piano four hands and percussion 1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - "Dushkajinks" for two pianos, flute, recorder, violin and cello ("played at family concert in Winnetka about 1946-47"), circa 1946-47 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - "Eight Voices" (Box 13, Folder 7a)
      - "Episode No. I" for flute, violin, and piano (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - "Episode Nos. II and III" for flute, clarinet, and bassoon (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - "Episode No. IV" for oboe, clarinet, and bassoon (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - "Fantasy for Three" for flute, marimba, and double bass (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - "47 Measures for 1107" (Box 13, Folder 11a)
      - "Four Plus Four" for strings and winds (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - "Gaelic Fantasy" for recorders, strings, and piano (manuscript) (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - "Gaelic Fantasy" for recorders, strings, and piano (transparency) (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - "Impromptu for Two Pianos" (written for Alice and Fay Taylor) (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - "Morris Dance Fantasy" for strings and winds (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - "Octet" for woodwinds (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - "Percussion Plus: Suite" for flute, bass, and percussion (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - "Pour s'amuser: Suite" for marimba, flute, oboe, clarinet, and basoon (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - "Precision Patterns: Suite for Percussion Ensemble," dedicated to Randall Edson 1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - "Quartet Opus 44" for flute, clarinet, bassoon, and piano 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - "Quick-step" for flute, oboe, clarinet, and bassoon (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - "Quintet for Amanda" for oboe and string quartet 1956 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - "Quintet for Flute and String Quartet" (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - "Quintet for Horn and Strings" 1973 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - "Quintet" in four movements for flute, violin, viola, cello, and piano 1950 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - "Recorder Quartet in D Minor," 1960 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - "Retrospective" for five winds and piano (manuscript) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - "Retrospective" for five winds and piano (transparency) (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - "Septet for Brass" (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - "Sonata for Two Harpsichords" (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - "Sonata for Two Violincelli and Piano" (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - "Suite for Six" for flute, clarinet, violin, viola, cello, and harpsichord (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - "Suite for Three" for two recorders and clarinet, or two flutes and viola (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - "Suite for Two Alto Recorders" 1961 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - "A ThanCare Piece" for violin and piano (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - "Three Short Flights for Four Flutes, dedicated to Susan Stockhammer 1975 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - "Time Out" for percussion and piano (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - "Trio" for piano, violin and cello, dedicated to Mary Jane Metcalf 1976 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - "Trio Sonata" for viola, cello, and piano 1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Solo pieces
      - "Berceuse for Nadia" for violin and piano 1949 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - "For Lelah" for cello and piano 1949 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - "A Gay Set: Piano Pieces for Second or Third Year of Study" 1961 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - "Inconsequential for David Alex" for flute and piano 1949 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - "A Method of Study for the Alto Recorder" (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - "Nine Piano Pieces" for about third year study (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - "A Short Piece for Virginal and Piano" (written for Fay and Alice Taylor) (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - "Sonata for Bassoon and Piano," dedicated to Bob and Kay Moore 1975 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - "Sonata for Flute and Piano" (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - "Sonata for Horn and Piano," dedicated to Dennis Behm 1974 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - "Suite for Solo Marimba" (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - "Three Moods" for flute and piano (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Choral works
      - "Canaan Bound: Cantata" for chorus and orchestra 1948, rev. 1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - "Canaan Bound: Cantata" for chorus and orchestra, piano reduction (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - "The Flower" for women's chorus and woodwinds (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - "Interpretations: Cantata" for mixed chorus and orchestra (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - "Interpretations: Cantata" for mixed chorus and orchestra (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - "The Light of Man" from the Brihadaranyaka Upanishad, for mixed chorus, woodwinds, and piano (manuscript) (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - "The Light of Man" from the Brihadaranyaka Upanishad, for mixed chorus and orchestra: full score and parts (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - "On Paumonok Shore" for women's chorus, reader, flute, and piano: full score and vocal parts (manuscript and transparency) 1958 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - "Songs of the Bards of Bengal" for women's chorus, flute, strings, and piano: full score and parts (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - "Ten Poems in a Filagree" for women's chorus, flute, piano, and string quartet: full score and parts (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - "Tensions" for mixed chorus (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - "Three Madrigals" for mixed chorus (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Three Songs for Women's Voices: The Old Soldier, Prince of Sleep, and Ship of Rio (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Juvenilia
      - "Etude" for piano (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - "French Suite" for piano 1928 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - "An Irish Courtship" for piano 1921 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - "A Joke" for piano 1921 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "Poltarnees" for piano (manuscript) (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - "Poltarnees, Beholder of Oceans," a musical pantomime for piano, published by Smith College Clef Club undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - "Prelude" for piano 1927 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Smith College exercises 1922-23 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "Sonatine for Violin and Piano," 1928 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - "Toccata" for piano 1924 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (arrangements; transcriptions; and pieces by Gertrude Smith and unidentified)
      - "Christmas Round" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Song in the Songless" for contralto, clarinet, and piano (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Trudle's Lighter Moment" for piano and voice [by D.S.D.?] (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - "Americana Collection": manuscript and mimeograph scores of American song arrangements (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - "Collection of First Songs for Children": songs by others [to be arranged?] (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - J.S. Bach, "Chorale and Aria" from "Cantata No. 153," transcribed for orchestra; and "From Cantata No. 4" (arranged by D.S.D.) (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Brahms, "Romanze" for chamber orchestra: full score and parts (arranged by D.S.D.) (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Fischer, "Six Fugues" transcribed for horns, trumpet, and trombone [arranged by D.S.D.?] (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Grieg, "Norwegian Suite" for orchestra and piano (arranged by D.S.D.) (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Marais, "Five Old French Dances" for winds and strings, or recorders and strings (arranged by D.S.D.) (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Mozart, "Divertimento I" and "Divertimento II" (cello part only) [arranged by D.S.D.?] (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Mozart, "Tempo di Menuetto": orchestral parts (arranged by D.S.D.] (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Pachelbel and J.S. Bach, "Four Fugues" transcribed for winds and brass [by D.S.D?] (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - "Chuckatuck, Walla Walla," piece for speaking chorus (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - "We Wish a Happy Birthday" (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - "Three songs for Women's Voices with Wind Instruments" (Box 17, Folder 26)